Okay, so let's talk
about the five levels of
conflict that is identified
for an agile project.
Okay, so the five levels of conflict then
are problem solving, disagreement,
contest, Crusade and World War.
And seriously, they are called Crusade and
World War, all right?
More about that in just second.
Let's talk about each one of these in
turn.
So first one, then, problem solving.
Level one, level one conflict is problem
solving.
And as their name suggests, team members
come together, they have an issue,
they have a problem, they have a
disagreement, and they resolve it.
So team members collaborate to resolve the
issue.
So whatever the issue is, and in this
case, it's not going to be a major issue.
It's going to be, let's
say, for example, you're
looking at relative
estimating of user stories.
So one team member is saying this is a
large user story.
Another team member is saying it's a small
user story.
Right.
Well, there's a disagreement.
However, that can easily be resolved.
Team members are going to work together.
They're going to collaborate to resolve
that issue.
Now, the level two then, the next level of
agile conflict is known as a disagreement.
In a disagreement now, the key here is
team members are now becoming opinionated.
So they're not really working together as
such now, right?
They're becoming opinionated, right?
It's my way or the highway type of thing,
right?
So each person believes that only their
solution is going to work, right?
So the other person's opinion doesn't
really matter.
They just believe, oh, it's only my work.
This is the only way it's going to work,
right?
So that's what disagreement is now.
Then the next level, level three,
something called contest.
And contest now is, now team members are
taking sides, right?
Team members are beginning to take sides.
And the focus now is
on winning, right, rather
than what the actual
solution really should be.
So, beginning to form clicks, for example.
Some team members are going on this side,
some people are
supporting the other person.
So just like any kind of contest,
right, think of a sports game.
You've got two teams.
What's the focus?
They need to win, right?
They need to score as many goals as
possible or, you know, whatever the game is.
And they need to win, right?
And so that's what the, that's what this
is analogous to.
Now, level four then is known as a
crusade.
And a crusade now, teams are polarized.
I teams are polarized.
And again, the goal
is simply to win without
considering what the correct solution is.
Team members, that's what they're focused
on, right?
And it's focused on protecting your own
team members.
So this side and this side, you're just
focused on protecting, you know,
so that's really what the focus is,
right?
Not on what the solution is going to be,
right, but who's going
to win in this case?
And then you have level five, which is
World War, and World War basically.
means, teams are not talking to each
other.
Team members are just
not talking to one another,
they're not listening to
anyone else's solutions.
They don't care about the other person or
the other group, the other team.
So it's just, you know,
like I said, team members
are just not talking
to one another at all.
That would be considered World War.
Now make sure you know what these five
conflict levels are.
It's always easy to remember.
I mean, everybody remembers four in five,
everyone remembers
Crusade and World War, right?
It's the first three that, you know,
you can, you can forget, right?
So make sure you remember, remember the
first three as well, right?
So it's problem solving, disagreement,
contest, and then Crusade and World War.